<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>OpenStreetMap - Tag - Filip Czaplicki</title><link>https://starsep.com/tags/openstreetmap/</link><description>OpenStreetMap - Tag - Filip Czaplicki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 20:52:32 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://starsep.com/tags/openstreetmap/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OpenStreetMap Software Projects</title><link>https://starsep.com/posts/osm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 20:52:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://starsep.com/posts/osm/</guid><description><![CDATA[I&rsquo;ve been contributing to OpenStreetMap for a few years now. Basically it&rsquo;s a map that anyone can edit: Wikipedia for maps.
I maintain a few software projects related to OpenStreetMap:
openaedmap-frontend: frontend of OpenAEDMap project it&rsquo;s a worldwide map of automated external defibrillators data comes from OpenStreetMap users can add new AEDs directly on our website osm-wtp-compare hosted at https://starsep.com/osm-wtp/ compares public transport data from Warsaw Transport Authority with OpenStreetMap it&rsquo;s a tool for finding errors and missing data in public transport data more details in this blog post (only in Polish) NextbikeOSM, RooveeOSM, and MevoOSM tools for comparing bike-sharing data with OpenStreetMap: Nextbike, Roovee, and Mevo respectively forked from javnik36/NextbikeOSM hosted at https://starsep.]]></description></item><item><title>JOSM: Bing StreetSide with Utilsplugin2 => Open custom URL</title><link>https://starsep.com/posts/josm-bing-custom-url/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 18:55:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://starsep.com/posts/josm-bing-custom-url/</guid><description><![CDATA[Bing StreetSide is alternative to Google Street View which can be used for OpenStreetMap mapping. There is a MicrosoftStreetside plugin for JOSM but it doesn&rsquo;t work for me due to dependencies of JavaFX/360 views.
I have managed to use it via Utilsplugin2.
Edit =&gt; Preferences (F12) =&gt; Utilsplugin2 settings Add new row with name Bing StreetSide and url https://www.bing.com/maps?cp={#lat}%7E{#lon}&amp;lvl=19.0&amp;style=x.
In the case of issues one can edit customurl.txt. For Linux/Flatpak it&rsquo;s located at ~/.]]></description></item></channel></rss>