<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - Filip Czaplicki</title><link>https://starsep.com/posts/</link><description>All Posts | Filip Czaplicki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 21:35:26 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://starsep.com/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CLI</title><link>https://starsep.com/posts/cli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 21:35:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://starsep.com/posts/cli/</guid><description>This is the list of CLI tools I found useful someday. It is useful reference as remembering all script names and options is cumbersome. Especially those I use rarely.
ripgrep rg (ripgrep): great grep replacement.
Recursive search and respects .gitignore by default.
Possible to configure per repository with .rgignore
Useful options:
-i: case insentive -v: invert matching -A n(after), -B n(before), -C n(context). n is number of lines -u, -uu, -uuu: unrestricted searching with gitignored, hidden, and binary files -l: list files matching -e: pattern (regex) to search for.</description></item><item><title>Nix</title><link>https://starsep.com/posts/nix/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 14:49:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://starsep.com/posts/nix/</guid><description>What is Nix? I recently started using Nix. It is a package manager and a build system. It uses its own functional programming language. At the moment I use it only as a package manager. For years, I maintained Ansible playbook for setting up my development environments. Nix allows to simplify it and eventually might even replace it. Instead of installing software via apt/pipx/downloading binaries from GitHub I use Nix.</description></item><item><title>JOSM: Bing StreetSide with Utilsplugin2 => Open custom URL</title><link>https://starsep.com/posts/josm-bing-custom-url/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 18:55:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://starsep.com/posts/josm-bing-custom-url/</guid><description><![CDATA[Bing StreetSide is alternative to Google Street View which can be used for OpenStreetMap mapping. There is a MicrosoftStreetside plugin for JOSM but it doesn&rsquo;t work for me due to dependencies of JavaFX/360 views.
I have managed to use it via Utilsplugin2.
Edit =&gt; Preferences (F12) =&gt; Utilsplugin2 settings Add new row with name Bing StreetSide and url https://www.bing.com/maps?cp={#lat}%7E{#lon}&amp;lvl=19.0&amp;style=x.
In the case of issues one can edit customurl.txt. For Linux/Flatpak it&rsquo;s located at ~/.]]></description></item></channel></rss>